Dear Zachary: A Letter to a Son About His Father is a
documentary, crime film directed by Kurt Kuenne.
In 2001, Andrew Bagby, a medical resident, is murdered not
long after breaking up with his girlfriend.
Soon after, when she announces she's pregnant, one of Andrew's many close
friends, Kurt Kuenne, begins this film, a gift to the child.
Self (voice), played by Kurt Kuenne.
Self (archive footage), played by Andrew Bagby.
Self - Father, played by David Bagby.
Self - Mother, played by Kathleen Bagby.
Self - Ex-Girlfriend (archive footage), played by Shirley Turner.
Self - Son (archive footage), played by Zachary Andrew Turner.
Dear Zachary: A Letter to a Son About His Father is a 2008 American documentary film
written, produced, directed, edited, shot and scored by Kurt Kuenne.
It is about Kuenne's close friend Andrew Bagby, who was murdered after
ending a relationship with a woman named Shirley Jane Turner.
Turner was arrested as a suspect, and, shortly thereafter, announced she was
pregnant with Bagby's child, a boy she named Zachary Turner.
The film premiered at the Slamdance Film Festival in 2008 and received a limited
theatrical release before being acquired for distribution by MSNBC.
It received critical acclaim, particularly for its editing and emotional weight.
Kuenne donated all profits from the film to scholarships
established in the names of Andrew and Zachary Bagby.
In 2009, after watching the film Canadian MP Scott Andrews introduced Bill C-464
(also known as "Zachary's Bill") to the Parliament of Canada.
The bill, which helps protect children in relation to bail hearings and
custody disputes, was signed into law the following year.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, parent child relationship,
grandparent grandchild relationship, loss of loved one, pregnancy.
The tone is uplifting.